Erin James

UX/UI Designer



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Skilled in UX design with over 10 years of teaching experience in the visual arts, bringing outstanding communication skills, strong leadership qualities, and polished design abilities, exceeding expectations and seeking to enrich the lives of diverse populations.

EXPERTISE

- Innovative Problem Solving
- Presenting & Communication
- Diversity & Inclusion

- Agile UX
- Creative Collaboration
- Building Rapport

- Empathy & UCD
- Branding & Visual Design
- Team Management

EXPERIENCES

Freelance UX Designer

VARIOUS NON-PROFITS | MAY 2022-PRESENT

- Helping non-profit organizations improve their website user experience and/or design their websites to extend their reach.
- Conducting user interviews, collecting data, creating user journeys and flows to inform decisions, wireframes & prototypes.
- Using Figma & presentation skills to optimize and present concepts and deliverables to teams and stakeholders.

UX/UI Designer Intern

FLATIRONS COMMUNITY CHURCH | JUNE 2022-PRESENT

- Utilizing agile UX/UI design and front-end development skills to implement web pages from concept to launch.
- Achieving impactful user experiences through working collaboratively with design, tech, and marketing teams to ensure brand and vision alignment.

E-commerce Small Business Owner

ROCK AND ROSE DEPOT | MAY 2020-JAN 2022

- Used Agile marketing principles to develop and design an online marketing strategy and increased conversion rates by 6.4%
- Empathetically met user needs during online learning by creating personalized laptop sleeves for students to boost morale and promote a positive learning culture.

Visual Arts Teacher

WINDSOR CHARTER ACADEMY | AUG 2012-JULY 2015

- Created & instructed a compelling curriculum for the Yearbook class that incorporated digital programming, photography, and journalism skills that resulted in the yearbook receiving the prestigious "Program of Excellence Award" in the first year.
- Team leader who used data & digital assessments to ideate and implement a successful school-wide positive behavior reinforcement plan that decreased negative student behavioral issues by 20%.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

UX/UI Design Certificate
Front End Development Specialization
CareerFoundry 2022

Post-Baccalaureate Licensing Art K-12 University of Northern Colorado, CO 2010 Bachelor of Arts in Studio Art, Cum Laude
Ouachita Baptist University/AR
2004

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Sister Carmen Community Center Community garden, food bank

Heritage Point HOA
Treasurer

Flatirons Community Church
UX/UI Design, Small group leader